本片基於真實事件改編
紐約州  長島
謝謝  謝謝大家
Well, thank you, thank you all,
羅斯林校園明星榜
各位家長和鎮上的倡導者們
parents and town advocates alike,
歡迎你們出席今晚的特別活動
for joining us on this very special evening.
今晚我們齊聚一堂
We're here tonight to kick off
共同迎接有史以來最前程遠大的一學年
our most ambitious school year yet.
各位  根據我們統計的數據
We've run the numbers, and folks,
我得到的最簡單的結論就是
there's no simpler way for me to put it.
我們的孩子們越來越聰明了
Our children are getting smarter.
兩位考進哈佛  兩位考進達特茅斯
Harvard, two. Dartmouth, two.
三位考進耶魯
Yale, three.
七位考進賓大
U Penn, seven.
謝謝大家
Thank you.
各位受托人們
...and my fellow trustees
你們已經用了整整一年
who wait all year long
根據高考成績和大學錄取率
ranking the top public schools in America
來給美國的頂尖公立學校排名
based on SATs and college acceptance rates.
羅斯林高中位列第四
And Roslyn is four.
現在  我想請出讓這一切成真的人
And now, I'd like to bring out the man responsible.
-恭喜  -謝謝
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
在任的這十年間
In his ten years here,
他改進了我們的教育體制
he's revamped our education system.
從學前班到高中無所不包
From pre-K all the way to high school.
請和我一起歡迎他上台
Please join me in welcoming to the stage
我們的學區主管和我的朋友
our district superintendent and my friend,
弗蘭克·塔索內
Frank Tassone.
壞教育
卡巴雷餐廳
羅斯林公立學校
羅斯林高中
早上好
Good morning.
你好  早上好
Hey there, good morning.
鬥牛犬隊加油
Go Bulldogs.
克普先生怎麼樣了
Have we heard about Mr. Kopple?
-他妻子生了雙胞胎  -雙胞胎
- Wife had twins. - Twins!
-昨天深夜的時候  -真好  給他們送點花
- Late last night. - Nice. Send over flowers
可能再送點吃的
and maybe an edible arrangement.
能不能把這些東西收拾掉
Can we, can we get these things out of here?
-它們可以鼓舞士氣  -是啊
- Oh, they're nice for morale. - Yeah, it'd be even nicer
如果排第一就更有用了
if they were shaped like ones.
-塔索內博士  -你好
- You know, Dr. Tassone... - Hey.
一位智慧的女性曾說過  不要追求你想要的
A wise woman once said it's not having what you want.
-而是珍惜你擁有的  -格盧金夫人
- It's wanting what you got. - Mrs. Gluckin.
我差點沒認出你來
I barely recognize you anymore what with the new name,
你換了新的名字  辦公室  職稱
new office, new job title.
薪水和文書工作還是老樣子
The same pay, same paperwork.
七八月份的賬目都結清了
July and August are all settled up.
-費用都登記存檔了  -太棒了
- Expenses booked and archived. - Perfect.
我還有點別的要和你談談
And something else I wanted to talk to you about...
安全門的問題也都處理好了
Safety gates are all taken care of.
我今天會去市政廳和他們討論具體策略
I'm meeting with City Hall later today to go over strategy.
老天  有人今天幹勁十足啊
Jeez, someone's had their coffee.
-沒錯  -塔索內博士
- Yeah. - Uh, Dr. Tassone?
-什麼事  -你週五去維加斯開會的航班
- Yeah. - Uh, did you want your flight
是想從肯尼迪國際機場還是紐瓦克機場起飛
to the Vegas conference Friday out of JFK or Newark?
謝了  小珍  哪個便宜選哪個
Thanks, J. Whatever's cheaper works fine.
瑪麗·安  你能幫我
And, uh, Mary Ann, is there any way
買杯減肥蔬果昔嗎
you'd be able to grab my diet smoothie?
-我要遲到了  -沒問題
- I was running late. - Oh, sure.
但還有件事
Uh, but there's one more thing.
卡蘿爾·施魏策爾從六點半開始
Carol Schweitzer's been camped up
就賴在會議室不肯走了
in the conference room since 6:30.
-她說她找您有急事  -我知道了
- Says it's urgent she speaks with you. - Okay, okay.
-查德  -查德  查德·施魏策爾的
- Chad. - Chad, Chad Schweitzer's...
好的  我來解決
Okay, I'll take care of it.
-謝了  -祝你好運
- Thanks. - Good luck.
少來
Stop it.
幫我們所有人一個忙
Do us all a favor.
他要是一小時還沒出來  記得報警
If he's not out of there in an hour, call 911.
我就在這堣@直砸門
And I am banging down doors
直到有人
until somebody here
認真聽我說話  懂嗎
takes me seriously. All right?
那個姓米利措克的  她偏心  知道嗎
That Militzok, she plays favorites, okay?
考試的時候她甚至都不讓他上廁所
She wouldn't even let him take a bathroom break
他有膀胱過動癥
during the test, and he has a hyperactive bladder.
查德  親愛的  告訴他你怎麼
Chad, honey, tell him how you...
我這埵野鷘憟芘}的證明  好吧
you know what, I have a note here from his doctor, okay?
施魏策爾夫人  請您冷靜一下
Ms. Schweitzer, just, just calm down.
-讓我們來...  -沒人肯聽我說話
- Let's, let's just... - No one will listen to me.
我不知道我還能怎麼辦
All right, I don't know what else I'm supposed to do.
查德  他和他同年級的學生一樣聰明
Chad, he is just as gifted as everyone else in his year.
-當然  -而且
- Absolutely. - And...
我很害怕  塔索內博士
I'm scared, Dr. Tassone,
因為如果他進不了實驗班
because if he doesn't get into OMNI...
覺得自己不如...
and he starts to think of himself as less than...
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不  我會和米利措克老師談的
No, I will talk to Ms. Militzok.
我會把這事解決的
I will straighten this whole thing out.
-你會嗎  -我保證
- You will? - Yes.
然後我們可以讓查德補考一次
And, and we'll just set a make-up test for Chad.
給他足夠的時間上廁所
All right, with ample bathroom time.
謝謝您  塔索內博士
Thank you, Dr. Tassone.
您不知道我有多感激您
I can't tell you how much I appreciate that.
沒必要謝我  好嗎
There's no need to thank me, all right?
查德是個聰明的孩子  有大好的人生等著他
Chad's a smart kid with the world ahead of him,
而我們的工作就是給他鋪好跑道
and it's our job to give him the runway.
謝謝您
Thank you.
說起來很有意思
It's funny.
查德  我像你這麼大的時候
You know, Chad, when I was your age,
我都進不了數學高班
I didn't even place into fast track math.
-真的嗎  -真的  我搞不定乘法口訣
- Really? - No. I couldn't nail my times tables.
那時候我以為我完了
And at the time, I thought my world was ending.
但我後來趕上大家了  你猜怎麼樣
But I caught up. You know what?
現在數學課歸我管
Now I set the math curriculum.
感謝您  塔索內先生
您是個很棒的學區總監  感謝您上課時給我們帶的披薩
傑茜卡
雪天魔杖
延長壽命
征服衰老和死亡
有什麼我能幫你的嗎
Can I help you with something?
不用  沒事
Oh, no, it's okay.
我來找克雷莫納夫人
I'm just here for Mrs. Cremona.
-或者叫格盧金夫人  -她現在不在
- Or Gluckin. - Ooh, she's not here,
但我很樂意解答你的問題
but I'm more than happy to answer any questions if...
-真的嗎  -真的
- Really? That would... - Mm-hmm, yeah.
你要是在忙的話我不想打擾你  但是
I don't wanna bother you if you're busy, but...
沒事  進來吧  歡迎你來打擾我
No, come on in, bother me.
我在做電子錶格  進來吧
I'm doing spreadsheets. Come, come in.
請坐
Take a seat.
我們好像沒見過
I don't think we've had a chance to meet.
-我叫蕾切爾  -蕾切爾  對了
- It's Rachel. - Rachel, right.
你是尼爾的妹妹
Neil's little sister.
對  你記性真好
Yeah. Wow, good memory.
我希望他沒在西北大學惹麻煩
I hope he's keeping out of trouble over at Northwestern.
沒  他很喜歡那  他選了生化專業
Yeah, he loves it. He's doing bio-chem.
那堛熒s聞專業也不錯
Ah, well, they have great journalism there, too.
是不錯
Yes, they do.
好的  他們想讓我寫一篇有關
Okay, so they just, they want me to write an article
新預算方案堛漱挩艨等堛漱撜
about the SkyWalk proposal in the new budget.
我只需要引述一句行政處的話就行了
And I just need a pull quote from administration.
沒問題  你是要錄音  好的
Yeah, oh, okay. A sound bite, nice.
我們一直在徵求高中生的意見
We've been asking high schoolers
想讓他們的生活更輕鬆一些
how we can make their day easier,
然後我們提出了天橋這個想法
so we came up with this idea, the SkyWalk.
它是一座連接學校兩端的橋樑
a bridge, to link the school from end to end.
這對我們來說是一項艱巨的任務
And um, it's a huge undertaking for us.
等明年五月這個計劃獲批
And we can't wait to break ground
我們會即刻動工的
once the plans are approved next May.
好極了  這就夠了  太感謝了
Great, that's all I need. Thank you so much.
這就夠了  你不需要後續問題嗎
That's it? No, no follow-ups?
不用  這就是篇拍馬屁的文章
No, it's just a puff piece.
他們把真正的報道留給高三學生寫了
They save the real stories for seniors.
蕾切爾
Rachel.
這不拍馬屁的文章  除非你決定這麼寫
It's only a puff piece if you let it be a puff piece.
西北大學也會這麼告訴你的
That's what they'll tell you over at Northwestern.
好嗎  一個真正的新聞工作者
All right? A real journalist
能把任何作業都寫成一篇報道
can turn any assignment into a story.
你在忙嗎  就一幫同事想向你道謝
Are you busy? Just a couple of colleagues want to convey thanks.
蕾切爾·巴爾加瓦  《山峰燈塔》的撰稿人
Rachel Bhargava, staff writer for the "Hilltop Beacon."
這位是鮑勃·斯派塞  學校董事會主席
This is Bob Spicer, school board president.
你是...
Oh, you're,
你跟我女兒貝卡一個年級對吧
You're in my daughter, Becca's year, right?
替我向你爸爸問好
Say hi to your dad for me.
很高興見到你  蕾切爾
Nice to meet you, Rachel.
如果還有問題  就和瑪麗·安約個時間  好嗎
And if you want to follow up, just set a time with Mary Ann, okay?
我等著看你的文章
And, uh, I'll be keeping an eye out for your byline.
需求量跟瘋了一樣  一飛沖天
The demand is insane. It's skyrocketing.
羅斯林高地的三室房
We're seeing three bedrooms go
要價超過一百萬
for over a million in Roslyn Heights.
是啊  賽奧西特和傑堿
Yeah, you just don't see those kinds of numbers
可看不到這種房價
in Syosset or Jericho.
沒錯  但那些鎮子離市塈騠
Right, but those towns are a further commute from the city.
曼哈西特和大頸也不行
Not Manhasset, not Great Neck.
重點是公立學校  學校越好
It's the public schools. The better the school system,
房價越高  就這麼簡單
the higher the price tag on the homes, period.
自從那本期刊上登了那篇報道
Our firm has sold nine separate lots in that area
我們公司已經在那婼璆X九塊地了
since the report in that journal came out.
這是一點心意
And, uh, here's a little something
-是大家的謝禮  -好吧
- you know, from all of us. - Okay.
天啊  這真是
Really, that's, oh.
-繼續保持吧  -謝謝大家
- Keep up the good work. - Well, thanks, everyone.
-塔索內博士  -對了
- Dr. Tassone? - Oh, yeah.
-你們介意合個影嗎  -沒問題
- Do you mind if we get a little... - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-我會放我辦公室  -好極了
- Something for my office. - Great.
-我很感謝你們  -靠過來點  威爾
- I really appreciate you... - Scoot in, scoot in, Will.
今天來看我
...coming in today.
-謝謝你們  -好的
- Thank you. - Okay.
-好的  謝謝你們  -好的
- Okay, thank you. - Okay.
好了  讓他
All right? Yeah, let's let him...
-讓他回去工作吧  -謝謝
- Let him get back to work. - Thank you.
-真的很感謝你們  -好的
- No, I really appreciate it. - Yeah.
-非常感謝  -謝謝
- Thank you so much. - Thank you.
好了
Okay.
我不能吃這些  麻煩你
I can't eat these. Just, if you put them out
把它們放外面讓大家隨便拿吧
for everybody to pick at, that'd be great.
他們沒有亞麻籽了
They were out of the flax seed.
沒關係  謝了
That's okay, that's okay. Thanks.
你覺得鮑勃那個職位大概能掙多少
How much do you figure a guy like Bob makes at his regular job?
你是說鮑勃·斯派塞嗎
Bob Spicer, you mean?
一年至少幾十萬
High sixes a year, minimum.
甚至可能超過百萬
Maybe seven figures in this market.
-怎麼了  -當我沒問
- Why? - Oh, forget it.
你看上去很累
You look tired.
也許你可以早點回家  休息一下
You might wanna go home early, get some rest.
我還得去聊狄更斯
I gotta run Dickens.
也許我可以試試退出
Maybe I'll try and bow out and
提早為這週末的維加斯之旅做好準備
get a headstart and early prep for Vegas this weekend.
-最好不要翹讀書俱樂部  -為什麼
- I wouldn't bail on book club. - Why?
那些女人喜歡你
Those women adore you,
而她們每人都有二十來個閨蜜
and each one talks to two dozen more.
距離下一次預算投票也就九個月了
The next budget vote's only nine months away.
-對  我們的天橋  -是啊  這是個大項目
- Right, our SkyWalk. - Yeah, the SkyWalk is big.
能讓我們排第一  這才是重點
Gets us to first. That's all that matters.
這個新的減肥食譜真夠我受的
This new diet is kicking my ass.
這到底是什麼
What is that, even?
估計是木炭之類的東西
It's got charcoal in it or something like that.
炭  是吧
Yeah, coal.
現在要是能來點碳水讓我殺人都行
I would kill somebody for a carb right now.
真不知道該上哪去找啊
I don't know where you could find one.
你真是賤死了
You are such a bitch.
怎麼  你想來一口嗎
Oh, would you like a bite?
-我討厭熏牛肉配黑麥麵包  -想咬一口嗎
- I hate pastrami on rye. - You want a bite?
我知道你不喜歡
Yeah, I know you hate it.
張嘴
Open up.
-太他媽的好吃了  -是吧
- Fucking so good. - Right?
再來一口嘛
Come on, you can eat more.
別這樣  再吃一口
You got... come on, one more bite.
-我要殺了你  -我不會告訴別人的
- I will kill you. - I won't tell anyone.
我誰都不會說的
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
你還在長身體
You're a growing boy.
快吃吧  別廢話了
Come on. Eat the fuckin' sandwich.
我們開始吧
Let's get started.
我們可以開始了嗎  大家
Should we get started, everyone?
聊聊我們對《馬丁·翟述偉》的看法吧
What do we all think of "Martin Chuzzlewit"?
好吧
Okay.
弗蘭克  不是所有人都對文化感興趣
You know, Frank, the culture is not for everyone.
我覺得我們最終還是
Eh, I thought we wound up having a
進行了一場不錯的討論
really good discussion, ultimately.
弗蘭克  我可以問你一個私人的問題嗎
Frank, can I ask you a personal question?
可以
Sure.
就是
It's just that...
喬納他
Jonah's...
非常接受不了分居的事
you know, having a really hard time with the separation.
是啊  你知道施拉克特老師
Yeah. You know, Ms. Schlacter,
告訴我他開始對《香蕉船》感興趣了
uh, told me that he's opened up a little bit in Banana Splits?
沒錯  是的  我的天吶
Right, yeah, oh, my God. Yeah.
-謝謝你的指引  -這是我應該做的
- Thank you for getting him in. - No, of course.
這一切對我們來說太難了  而且
It has been so hard on us, and...
你真的是
You have been...
幫了我們的大忙
such a tremendous help.
莎倫  別這麼說  我很樂意幫忙  隨時都可以
Oh, Sharon, of course. Anytime, anytime.
是啊  我...
Yeah, and...
-弗蘭克  抱歉  -沒關係  沒關係
- Frank, I'm sorry. - No, no, no, no, no.
你想給你的兒子最好的安排
You want what's best for your son.
這沒有什麼好羞恥的
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
相反  它會讓你更堅強  只是
Uh, no, it makes you strong. It's, um...
我
I...
我覺得  到頭來
you know, I think at the end of the day,
她給我留下的回憶還是如此鮮活
her memory is still very fresh.
看見你我怎麼就一點都不吃驚呢
Somehow, I'm not surprised.
傑妮之前弄錯了幾份文件
Jenny screwed up some paperwork earlier.
我在給她善後
I'm saving her ass.
傑妮有個好姑媽
Jenny's got a good aunt.
狄更斯聊得怎麼樣了
How did Dickens go?
這周去的是莎倫·凱茨家
Well, it was Sharon Katz's place this week.
那個
And...
-我就知道  -我想我可能
- I knew it. - I, I think maybe
不該主動提出幫她洗碗
I shouldn't have offered to wash up.
可憐的女人
That poor woman.
她完全不是你的菜
She's nowhere near your type.
確實  完全不是
She's not, she's not.
-詹米森  -學術英語
- Jamieson. - Uh, Honors English.
-喜歡尼采  -很好
- Loves Nietzsche. - Very good.
迪詹納羅呢
Uh, DiGennaro?
迪詹納羅
Oh, DiGennaro.
社會研究
Social studies,
九年級世界歷...
ninth grade global hist...
美國歷史
American history.
在少年棒球聯盟當教練
Coaches Little League, too.
沒錯
Yes.
這些都太簡單了  難的來了
Well, these are too easy. Oh, here's a toughie.
托德亨特
Todhunter.
媽的
Oh, shit.
托德亨特  托德亨特
Todhunter, Todhunter...
托德亨特老師
Mr. Todhunter.
這個賽季的保齡球聯賽進展如何
How's that bowling league shaping up this season?
我們處在領先位置
We're ahead.
但我們週日有一場和耶利哥高中的大賽
But we've got our big match against Jericho on Sunday.
耶利哥啊  你肯定能殺他們片甲不留
Jericho, mm. I think you'll crush them.
謝謝你舉辦這場聚會
Thank you for putting this on.
歡迎老師們
感謝你們做的一切
-太貼心了  -沒什麼  我的榮幸
- This is so nice. - Oh, of course. My pleasure.
-弗蘭克  -我也只能做到這些
- Oh, Frank! - The least I could do.
-失陪一下  -弗蘭克
- Yeah, excuse me. - Hey, Frank.
所以
So, um...
要去拉斯維加斯了你激動嗎
hey, are you getting pumped for Vegas?
反正我是已經打包好了
'Cause, uh, I got my bags packed.
我已經準備好出發了
I'm ready to go.
是啊  離開老婆幾天
Yeah. It'll be good to get away from the wife
還是很不錯的
for a few days too, huh?
-是吧  -是啊
- Right? - Right.
離開個幾天
A few days, yeah.
你想知道承包商給的報價是多少
You want to know how many bids we got from contractors?
協作  進取
關於天橋建設
For the SkyWalk construction,
你們有過幾種不同的方案  是嗎
you explored several options, right?
-我們有過四五套方案  -好吧
- I think we had four or five. - Okay.
具體是哪些公司呢
From which firms, exactly?
等  等一下
Hang-hang on a sec.
你要寫的是個什麼文章
What's this article you're supposed to be writing?
是關於天橋的報道
Oh, it's a piece on the SkyWalk.
校園報想要深入地瞭解
And the student paper wanted a deep dive
建築細節嗎
into construction specs?
他們讓我自由發揮  某種程度上
They're giving me free reign, more or less.
我只是想找個有趣的切入點
I guess I'm just looking for an interesting way in.
-好吧  露絲  -蕾切爾
- Oh, okay, Ruth. - Rachel.
蕾切爾  那就讓我來給你的故事找個角度
Rachel, so let me give you a great angle for your story.
-你想寫下來還是  -我在錄音呢
- Okay. You wanna write this down or are you... - I'm taping.
那好
Okay.
天橋是一個偉大的項目
The SkyWalk is a great project.
它將會成為整個長島唯一的一座天橋
It'll be the first SkyWalk on all of Long Island,
也是羅斯林又一個
and yet one more reason Roslyn schools
碾壓耶利哥和西奧賽特的理由
put Jericho and Syosset to shame.
而且它看起來很漂亮  也會讓我們的生活更輕鬆
And it'll look great and make all our lives easier.
謝謝  結束  祝晚安好運
Thank you, the end. Good night and good luck.
還有什麼能幫你的嗎
What else can I help you with?
你手邊有報價的資料嗎
Do you have the bids handy?
還是說不在你手邊
Or are they not on you?
當然不在我手邊  都鎖在地下室
No, they're not on me. They're locked in the basement,
壓在一堆年鑒
lost in the annals of history.
我下節沒課
Well, I have next period free.
是嗎
Do you?
好吧
All right.
祝你能找到
Good luck finding 'em.
檔案館
你有什麼事嗎
Do you need somethin'?
複印點東西
Just a couple of photocopies.
好吧
Okay.
成功  尊重
-你今年高二嗎  -高一
- So you're a sophomore? - Junior.
我兒子傑克在貝爾莫爾讀高二
My son Jake is actually in the second grade over at Bellmore.
離這堣ㄓ蚖
You know, not too far from here.
在南海岸
South Shore, you know.
這棟樓太老了  經常漏水
It's an old building. We get leaks every so often.
通常稍等一會就不漏了
It usually stops after, like, a minute.
曼德勒海灣度假村
我們需要賭王  擲個十二點
We need a hard eight here. We need boxcars.
我們需要十二點  萊尼  十二點
We need boxcars, Lenny, we need boxcars.
在減少資源或將學習和成本聯繫起來的情況下提高績效
我知道你們在想什麼
I know what you're all thinking.
乍一看  這些數字可能讓人望而卻步
At first glance, these numbers might seem prohibitive
但我在這媟Q帶著遠見跟你們講
but I'm here to tell you that with some vision,
它們可以和諧共存
they can dovetail quite amicably.
我們可以看到  這個項目
As we can see, the added benefits
帶來的益處數不勝數
to such a program are remunerative.
我很想讓你看看我們在那堸答漕き
I'd love for you to see what we're doing out there
-如果你們什麼時候來長島  -我想
- if you're ever on Long Island. - Yeah, I think,
我想我們十一月十二月會去東海岸
I think we're on the East Coast in November, December.
-所以我  -我們也會在
- So I'll... - Well, we're there.
很好  太好了
Good, good, good, good. Okay.
走之前過來喝一杯
And listen, stop by and have a drink before you leave.
-好嗎  -那太好了
- All right? - That was terrific.
-謝謝  -保重
- Thank you. - Take care.
很好
Great.
好吧
All right.
來點什麼
What can I get ya?
一杯蘇打水加青檸
Just a club soda with lime.
麻煩菜單給我看一下
And can I see your food menu, please?
還有
And...
凱爾
Kyle.
凱爾·康特拉斯
Kyle Contreras.
十五年前上普蘭多姆高中  是嗎
Plandome High maybe 15 years ago, right?
我以前在那兒教英語
Yeah, I used to teach English there.
塔索內博士
Dr. Tassone.
叫我弗蘭克吧
Frank.
弗蘭克
我以為我們前腳踏出校門
I would think that you would forget
你後腳就會把我們忘得一乾二淨
about us the minute we got out of there.
那你可就大錯特錯了
No, you'd be surprised.
有時候我倒希望可以忘掉
I mean, some things I wish I could forget.
你知道我希望忘記哪件事嗎
Yeah. You know somethin' I wish I could forget?
利普曼的假髮
Would be Lippman's hair piece.
你還記得那個
Do you remember that thing that...
那玩意...
That... with the...
天吶  利普曼的假髮
Oh, my God, Lippman's hair piece, Christ.
那你現在都做什麼
So, what do you, what do you...
在新學校教英語嗎
are you teaching English at the new place?
不  我現在做行政了
No, I'm, I'm administrative now.
類似校長嗎
Like a principal?
類似學校的主管
No, like superintendent of schools.
看看你  你就喜歡這麼說話
Look at that. You love saying that.
你就喜歡這樣  學校的主管
You love that. Superintendent of schools.
-還搖頭晃腦的  -我已經做了十二年了
- With the head, too. - I've done it for 12 years.
是很不錯的
I mean, look, it's great.
當然跟其它事情一樣  也會有利弊
It does have its trade-offs, like anything.
有時候我真的很想念講課
I really miss being back in the classroom sometimes
跟學生們一起
with my students, you know.
你怎麼樣了  還在寫作嗎
How about you? You, um, you still writing?
短篇  科幻小說  是吧
Short stories, science fiction, right?
我記得你以前到哪都帶著
I remember you used to carry around
那本破破爛爛的《沙丘》
that beat-up copy of "Dune" everywhere.
是啊  我寫那東西主要是為了
Yeah, I mostly just wrote that stuff
應付你的讀書報告
to get out of your book reports.
別這麼說  有一篇寫的非常好的
No, come on, come on. There was that really good one
那個關於外星殖民地的
about the, um, about the alien colony.
我在給你寫的石溪大學推薦信堣]提過  對吧
I talked about it in your rec for Stony Brook, right?
是啊  石溪大學
Yeah, yeah, for Stony Brook.
抱歉  我
Sorry, I, um...
我沒考上石溪大學
I burnt out at Stony Brook.
幾年以後  我
After a few years, I...
搬到了這
moved out here.
直到最近我一直在跳舞
I was dancing up until very recently.
跳舞
Dancing?
謝謝
Thank you.
那你妻子陪你一起出差嗎  還是
So does your wife come with you on these things, or...
她留在紐約了
Is she back in New York?
沒有沒有  我妻子過世了
No, no, no, my wife passed away.
-很抱歉  -沒事
- I'm sorry. - No, no, it's...
沒關係  都是很久以前的事情了
it's fine. It was a long time ago.
甚至要在我認識你以前了
It was before I had you, even.
吃的怎麼樣
How's the food?
難吃
Shit.
想去別的地方嗎
You wanna try somewhere else?
我以為你只待兩天
I thought you were here for two days.
就一個週末  對
Uh, just for the weekend, yeah.
一個週末需要這麼多西裝
A lot of suits for a weekend.
誰也猜不到會有什麼活動...
Well, you never know what might come up these...
好吧
Right.
你總是這樣  對吧
That was always your thing, wasn't it?
你做英語老師的時候
Even when you were an English teacher,
也總是西裝革履
you were always the guy in the suits.
西裝怎麼了
What's wrong with a suit?
說不清  就是...
I don't know, it's just...
有點悲哀
it's a little sad.
就是有點悲哀
Just a little sad.
冰箱埵n像...
I think they put some bottles in the, uh...
有幾瓶酒  我也不清楚原因
in the bar fridge, I'm not sure why.
你現在可以看我的眼睛了  弗蘭克
You're allowed to make eye contact, Frank.
不行
No, I'm not.
好吧
Right.
羅斯林大道
爸爸
Dad!
我帶晚餐回來了
I got dinner.
今天有什麼趣事嗎
Anything happen today?
我和副主管談了
I spoke to the assistant superintendent.
為了寫文章
For an article.
那位女士是管事的
The woman who runs all the business.
不知道他們想不想雇一位管培員工
Wonder if they're looking to hire anybody in development.
你資歷過高了
You're overqualified.
羅斯福影像
佛坦歐福鄉間老路
羅莎·貝爾莫墨西哥餐廳
萊斯利泳池用品店
加班到這麼晚啊  格盧金女士
Late night, Ms. Gluckin?
我的天  艾迪  你嚇死我了
Jesus, Eddie, you scared the shit out of me.
週末有什麼好玩的安排嗎
Got any fun plans for the weekend?
沒有  我只想回家安靜地
Yeah, no, all I want is to spend some quiet time
陪我的孩子
at home with my kids.
-你明白的  -好吧
- You know. - All right.
祝你愉快
Have a good time.
-下周見  -好  晚安  艾迪
- See you next week. - Yeah, good night, Eddie.
-抱歉  嚇到你了  -沒關係
- Sorry about scare... - That's all right.
他...
He's...
好吧  首先  他們太小了
Okay, first of all, they're too small.
姐妹們  你們認識我的侄女傑妮·阿奎拉嗎
Oh, girls, have you met my niece, Jenny Aquila?
她和我一起在羅斯林工作  是行政職員
She's working with me over at Roslyn, district clerk.
這地方可真美啊
Isn't this place beautiful?
-我覺得...  -太美了
- I mean... - So gorgeous.
那幾輛雪佛蘭  霍華德肯定賺了不少吧
Howard must be making out like a bandit with those Chevys.
他最近在兼職做咨詢
He's been consulting a little on the side.
我為他驕傲
I'm proud of him.
其實我們打算等到這學期結束就重新裝修
We're planning a big remodel once the season's through, actually.
你找了哪位承包商
Who's your contractor?
-媽  救命  -我兒子吉姆
- Ma, help! - Jim Boy's gonna do it.
大鵝被擊垮了  我不能...
Big goose down. I can't... Ah!
你確定吉米準備好接這麼大的工程了嗎
Are you sure Jimmy's ready to take on a project this size?
確定  對他也好
Yeah, it'll be good for him.
讓他專心於新事物
Get his mind going on somethin' new.
-帕姆姑媽  -什麼事
- Aunt Pam. - Yeah?
我可以和你進去聊幾句嗎
Uh, can I talk to you inside just for a sec?
好的
Sure.
好了  傑妮  什麼事
All right, Jen. What's going on?
說實話
Honestly...
提到這件事就很不好意思了  但是...
I feel bad even bringing it up, but, um...
傑克的生日要到了
Jake's birthday is comin' up.
他一直想要索尼遊戲機
And he's been asking for the Sony PlayStation.
-電子遊戲機  -是
- Video game system. - Yeah.
他總說朋友都有了  自己落後了
And how all his friends have it and how he feels left out.
你也知道
You know, um,
我手頭有點緊  我一直在想既然
money's been tight, and I was just thinking since
霍華德最近收入這麼好...
Howard's been doin' so well and all...
我有錢了馬上就還給你
I'd pay you back as soon as I'm able.
直接用卡吧
Just put it on the card.
安柏  親愛的  可以讓我
Amber, sweetie, do you mind
和你傑妮表姐單獨待一會嗎
giving your cousin Jenny and me a minute?
謝謝
Thank you.
但我想或許你可以通過私人渠道
But I was wondering if maybe you could just lend me
把錢借給我...
the money from your personal...
不用擔心  到了月底
Don't worry about it. It'll all be reconciled
全都會做平
at the end of the month.
我這樣做很久了
I've been doing this a long time.
只是  只是...
It's, it's just,
他很想要那台遊戲機
he wants that PlayStation so much, you know?
週一一早先把收據放到我桌上
Just put the receipt on my desk first thing Monday morning
不用多想
and don't give it another thought.
我先失陪了  要去招待客人
Now if you'll excuse me, I have to play host.
找出文章的主旨
山峰燈塔
我沒明白  這是什麼
I don't get this. What is this?
是你要的天橋報道
It's the SkyWalk piece you wanted.
不  這是兩頁的承包商投標
No, this is two pages of contractor bids,
建築材料和區劃條例
building materials, and zoning ordinances
非常詳細
in brutal detail.
對  這就是新聞報道
Yeah, it's journalism.
我們的讀者才十五歲
Our readers are 15.
你知道每期報紙我們都得在印刷前
You realize we have to submit every issue to Bressler
讓佈雷斯勒過目吧
before we go to print.
還有塔索內博士和帕姆·克雷莫納
And Dr. Tassone, and Pam Cremona.
帕姆·格盧金  她現在姓格盧金了
Pam Gluckin. It's Gluckin now.
聽我說  我們不是《紐約時報》  好吧
Look, we're not the "New York Times," right?
我們是個課外小組  是個
We're an extracurricular. We are a club
為了上好的大學而創辦的社團
designed to get us all into good colleges.
我們這堸絨纗D有特定的方法
We have a certain finesse to the way we approach stories here.
要我說的話  也難以描述
A je ne sais quoi, if you will.
但不用擔心  你會掌握的
But don't worry, though. You're gonna get the hang of it.
創記錄的天橋被證實是一項昂貴的工程
學生們對即將進行的天橋項目興奮不已
一流五金
羅斯林公立學校
詹姆斯·D·麥卡登
先生
Sir.
可以問一下嗎
Could I ask, uh,
你今天去了幾家我們的店
how many of our stores have you visited today?
好幾家吧
A couple.
法明代爾和伊斯利普的那幾家
The ones in Farmingdale and Islip
沒有我要的東西
didn't have what I was looking for.
我們其實為高級顧客
I mean, you know, we actually offer
提供免費的送貨服務
free ship-to service for our high-value customers.
你覺得我是高級顧客
You think I'm high-value?
當然是了
I mean, reasonably, yeah.
所以要把這些東西送到哪去
So where's this stuff going?
-該死  -好  不  不
- Shit. - Yeah, no, no.
-我和他說吧  不  他在這  -該死的
- I'll get him. No, he's right here. - Motherfucking shit.
不  他...不用擔心
No, he's... no worries.
親愛的  拜託  你知道我打球的時候
Honey, come on, you know how they feel
-討厭接電話  -是拉塈銣A
- about the phones on the course. - It's Larry, for you.
-我表弟  -拉  找我
- My cousin. - Larry, for me?
什麼
What?
好吧  告訴他我打完18桿就打給他
Okay, just tell him I'll call him after 18.
他說是學校的事
He says it's about the school.
拉...床墊公司的那位
Larry from... the mattress firm?
不  他現在在一流五金上班
No, he's over at Ace Hardware now.
這個孩子給了我的員工一個家庭住址
So this kid, he gives my guy a home address.
在西漢普敦
In Westhampton.
離羅斯林整整八十公里
Full 50 miles outside of Roslyn.
還是個家庭住址
And it's a home address.
所以我對自己說
You know? So I say to myself, I say,
"羅斯林學校的承包商
"What's a Roslyn school's contractor
為什麼會跑到塞爾登
"doing buying supplies
這麼遠的地方來買東西"
"all the way out in Selden for, anyway?"
不  我們不會的  我們不會的
No, we wouldn't, we wouldn't.
我們的物料都是批發購買的
We get our materials wholesale, anyway.
我們...我們會招標
We, we put out bids.
工具箱  淋浴頭  這都是家裝用的東西
Tool chest, shower heads. That's home improvement.
-不是學校用的東西  -沒錯  沒錯
- That's not school stuff. - That's right, right.
-說不通  鮑勃  -這位詹姆斯·麥卡登是誰
- It doesn't add up, Bob. - Who is this James McCarden
他為什麼會有羅斯林的公費卡
and why does he have a Roslyn expense card?
不知道  我都不認識姓麥卡登的
I don't know. I don't even know a McCarden.
羅斯林就沒有姓麥卡登的
There is no McCarden at Roslyn.
稍等  親愛的  帕姆·克雷莫納
Oh, hang on, honey, wasn't Pam Cremona
或者帕姆·格盧金  誰知道她姓什麼
or Gluckin or whatever she is,
她第一任丈夫是不是姓麥卡登
wasn't her first husband a McCarden?
拜託
Come on.
不可能  怎麼可能是帕姆·格盧金
No way. Pam Gluckin, of all people?
她要在杜恩路建一所房子
She's gonna have a house on Dune Road?
雪佛蘭科爾維特
-我們該怎麼說  -不  什麼都不用說
- What should we say? - No, there's nothing to say.
-收據就證明了一切  -好吧
- The receipts say everything. - Yeah, okay.
-但我們需要...  -好了  她就在你身後
- But we need to... - Okay, she's right behind you.
你好  帕姆
Hi, Pam.
我想感謝你們大家
And, uh, I want to thank you all
主動抽出自己的時間
for volunteering time out of your day
來和我交流  我很想
to speak with me. I would just
聽你們每個人說說希望在六年級
love to hear from each of you what you hope
達到什麼目標
to achieve in the sixth grade.
好  從你開始吧  海瑟
Yeah, let's start with you, Heather.
我想拿到全A的成績
I wanna get all A's and become
像我媽媽一樣成為一位心胸外科醫生
a cardiothoracic surgeon like my mom.
很好
Great, uh,
但是為了完成今天的任務
but just for the purposes of today...
你能不能...
if you could just...
-快來  -什麼
- Come. - What?
快點
Quick.
稍等  我馬上回來
One second. Okay, I'll be back.
協作  進取
成功  尊重
我們可能會被抓
We're vulnerable here.
她盜用了納稅人的三萬美元
She stole $30,000 in taxpayer money
這還只是付給一流五金的
and that's just between the Ace Hardware.
天知道還有誰有公費卡
Who knows who else got an expense card?
我和你說  我們在道德上有責任
I'm telling you, it's our moral responsibility
向鎮媮|報這件事  必須的
to report this to the town. We have to.
不  這是犯罪了
No, this is a criminal matter.
我們得報警  找聯調局
We've got to call the police, the FBI.
好的  我們的法律顧問說
Okay, that was our legal counsel.
他們建議我們上報
They do recommend we report.
很好  那就這麼定了
Great, okay, well then, that settles it.
我要打給市長
I'm gonna call the mayor.
弗蘭克  你要一起來打電話嗎
Frank, you wanna be on that call?
對不起  對不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
快來人  給他倒杯水
Go get him, get him a glass of water.
我應該發現這件事的  我應該檢查的
I should have caught this. I should have checked.
帕姆在這比我的資歷還深
Pam's been here longer than I have.
我都沒想過
I didn't even think.
不  不  不  弗蘭克  這...這不是你的錯
No, no, no, no, Frank. It's... it's not your fault.
她花了十年在我們所有人心中都建立了信任
She built up a decade's worth of trust with all of us.
我們都被蒙蔽了
We were asleep at the wheel.
謝謝
Thank you.
但在我們進一步行動之前  需要...
But before we go any further, we need to,
需要瞭解目前的情況
we need to know what we're dealing with.
菲爾在我辦公室  正在計算確切的數字
I have Phil in my office getting a firm number.
菲爾  我們的審計員
Phil, our auditor?
這個人應該被解雇
The man should be fired.
他是唯一一位應該有所察覺的人
He's the one person who should have caught wind of this.
-蠢貨  -好吧
- Prick. - Okay.
我們不能操之過急
We can't jump the gun here.
尤其是在這麼危急的情況下  好吧
Not when there's this much at stake, all right?
-我們能...  -好吧
- Can we... - Okay.
我們給他一小時時間
We'll give him an hour.
-但在這之後...  -好的
- That's... But then, after that... - Right.
-我們就得上報了  -好的
- we start making calls. - Right.
吉姆小子做事怎麼能
How could Jim Boy be so careless,
這麼不小心
going around like that?
裝修肯定不能讓他干了
I'm pulling him off the remodel, that's for sure.
這下得去找個正經包工頭了
Just gonna have to hire on a real contractor.
-專業人士  -嗯  帕姆
- A professional. - Yeah, Pam?
不不不  弗蘭克能擺平這事
No, no, no. Frank's gonna fix this.
他知道我對學校來說有多重要
He knows how important I am to this school.
是我在維持這堛犒B轉  明白嗎
I'm the one who keeps the lights on here, you know?
-他會告訴他們的  -你覺得會有人
- He'll tell 'em. - Do you think anybody
發現那台索尼遊戲機的事嗎
could ever find out about the PlayStation?
不會  我跟你說過我做平了
No, I told you I took care of that.
你完全不用擔心
You have nothing to worry about there.
那就好
That's good.
因為...
It's just, um...
我...
I, uh...
我週末可能還提前買了些
I might have also done a little early Christmas shopping
聖誕禮物
over the weekend, too.
我本來想等過完節再告訴你的
See, I wasn't gonna mention until after the holiday
因為我給你買了禮物
because I bought you something,
我不想毀了驚喜
and I didn't, I didn't wanna spoil it.
我發誓  我發誓  我打算把錢還上的
I swear, I swear, I was gonna reimburse it all.
多少錢
How much?
不多  那個...
Not much, you know. Just like, um...
大概...
maybe...
在羅德與泰勒百貨花了1600
$1,600 at Lord & Taylor and...
在梅西百貨花了1200
another 12 at Macy's.
弗蘭克能擺平這事
Frank's gonna fix this.
跟我匯報  菲爾
Give me good news, Phil.
這不可能  絕對不可能
There's no way. There's, there's no way.
有支票不見了
There's check warrants that are missing.
購買記錄  我相信了她的話
Purchase orders. I took her word for it.
她每次都有說法  讓我不用擔心
She would tell me one thing, she'd say don't worry about it,
我就像個蠢貨一樣信了她鬼話
and I believed her like the fucking idiot schmuck I am.
我從沒想過要檢查核實
Oh, I never even think to check up, to validate.
我要丟工作了  我們的事務所完蛋了
I'm gonna lose my job. I'm gonna lose our firm.
-我們死定了  他們會殺了我們  -等等  等等
- We're dead, they'll kill us. - Hey, hey, no, no, no...
沒人要殺人  菲爾  看著我的眼睛
Nobody's killing anybody. Phil, look me in the eye.
看著我的眼睛
Look me in the eye.
這塈A說了算  跟我重複
You're running the show here. Say it after me.
"這塈睇﹞F算"
"I am running the show."
-這塈睇﹞F算  -很好
- I am running the show. - Good.
振作點
Pull it together.
你具體發現少了多少錢
How much did you find concretely?
二十二萬零三千
Two hundred twenty-three.
具體金額  但這只是最明顯的部分
Concretely, but that's just the obvious stuff.
-誰知道還有多少...  -223000
- Who knows what else is buried... - $223,000.
好的  好的
Okay, okay.
我們就咬定這個金額
That's our number.
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
我們就跟董事會說這個金額  223000
That's the number we go back to the board with, 223.
不  你沒聽明白
No, you're not hearing me.
這可能只是冰山一角
That might just be the tip of the iceberg.
-你又不能確定  -弗蘭克
- Well, you don't know that. - Frank.
收據都不見了
The receipts are gone.
估計都進了碎紙機
They're in the bin of a shredder, probably.
可能是被她弄丟了
She could have misplaced them.
現在有個非常現實的可能性
I mean, there's a very real scenario here
其它所有支出可能都是正當的  對吧
where all the other expenses are legit, right?
-也許吧  我說不好  -菲爾  菲爾
- Maybe, I don't know. - Okay, Phil, Phil.
她又不是什麼犯罪大師
She's not some criminal mastermind.
帕姆是我們的朋友
All right, Pam is our friend,
她犯了個愚蠢的錯誤
and she has made a stupid mistake.
但是...
But what...
州審計長那邊怎麼辦
but what about the state comptroller?
海韋希隨時可以
Hevesi could barge into this office
闖進這間辦公室  進行外部審計
at any given moment, conduct an outside audit.
你工作了三十年  他有這麼做過嗎
Has he ever done that once in your 30 years of experience?
正是如此
Exactly.
你就
Just...
告訴我一個金額  然後
give me a number, and...
我來擺平董事會
I'll take care of the board.
好了  各位
Okay, okay, everyone.
那個
So, the, uh...
總額是二十五萬美元
the sum total is $250,000.
-什麼  -老天  開什麼玩笑
- What? - Jesus, are you kidding me?
-那女人可真有種  -我們...
- That woman has a set of balls on her. - We can just...
-我要讓她好看  -你沒機會了
- When I get my chance. - You never will.
拿索警方會處理她的
She's gonna be Nassau PD's for the taking.
-還有她那個混蛋兒子  -不不不
- And that shitbird son of hers. - No, no, no, no, no.
-不不不  鮑勃  -好了  我們得走正當途徑
- No, no, no, Bob. - Okay, all right, let's do this right.
-把手機放下  鮑勃  -為什麼
- Put the phone away, Bob. - And why should he?
因為我們會失去一切的
Because we will lose everything.
什麼意思  弗蘭克
What do you mean, Frank?
一旦帕姆這事傳出去
Once word gets out about Pam,
我們就是請《紐約時報》  《新聞日報》
we're inviting "The Times," "Newsday,"
以及三州地區的所有報紙
and every other paper in the tri-state area
-來上門報道  -恕我直言
- to our front door. - With all due respect,
去他的報紙  這事真真切切的犯罪
screw the papers. This is a very real crime here.
偷竊納稅人的錢
A theft of taxpayer money.
朱迪  你在學校董事會
Judy, you've served on the school board
工作多久了  七年
for how long, seven years?
-八年  我很自豪  -好的  在這八年間
- Eight, proudly, - Okay, and in eight years,
納稅人多少次順利通過了
how many times has our budget been passed
我們的預算
by taxpayers without incident?
-八次  -沒錯
- Eight. - Right.
那等五月份我們提出下一年預算的時候
So what happens when our next budget goes up
會是什麼情況
for approval in May?
我們努力了一整年的預算
The budget that we've worked all year on.
能幫我們通過天橋項目的經濟刺激
The stimulus that gets us the SkyWalk.
能幫我們登上第一的項目  會怎麼樣
That gets us to first. What happens?
我明白他的意思
I get what he's saying.
輿論會怎麼說
I mean, how's it going to look?
一個學校員工能偷竊
A school employee is able to take
數十萬美元的公款
hundreds of thousands of dollars from the coffer
而不被發現
without anyone noticing.
我們為什麼還要繼續給學校撥款
Why would we pump more money into the school system?
沒錯  如果這種重大醜聞傳出去
Right, if a scandal this seismic breaks,
我們的預算就完了
I mean, our budget is torpedoed, done.
我們得重頭開始了
We are right back to square one.
我不知道  到時候就開不出工資了
I don't know, you can't pay the teachers.
也許教員會跳槽
Maybe they start migrating out.
這不會影響到大學吧
This can't affect the colleges, huh?
我們得準備好  頂尖學校的
I think we'd have to expect that admissions
招生官對我們的看法
at top-tier schools would view us
可能會徹底改變
under a radically different lens, yeah.
不  等等  為什麼
No, wait, what, what, why would they ever?
如果他們察覺到有麻煩  那他們
If they smell trouble, then they...
說不好  他們可能暫時不考慮羅斯林的學生
I don't know, they might decide to lay off Roslyn kids for a while.
"錄取"可能一夜之間變成"拒絕"
"Yeses" can become "Nos" overnight.
我聽說過有先例
I've-I've heard of that happening before.
真的  總之  我們先...
I have. So anyway, let's just...
先設想一下  好嗎
let's tease this out, okay?
我們的錄取率不佳  排名下滑
We don't perform, we go down in the rankings.
然後我們的姐妹學校
And then our sister schools
把我們擠出前十  前一百
nose us out of the top ten, top hundred.
賽奧西特和傑堿  那幫混蛋
Syosset and Jericho, those sons of bitches.
那時候我們就會看到
And that's when we start seeing
房價受到負面影響
property values adversely affected.
他說的對  當然是對的
He's right. Of course he is.
就房地產來說
As far as real estate,
尤其是在長島
especially Long Island,
房價直接跟
a town is only as good as its...
公立學校的水平掛鉤
Public school system.
我們付出了那麼多努力  對吧
After everything we've worked for, huh?
那麼多年的努力才達到現在的程度
Years that it's taken to, to, to get this far.
這事關係到我們的孩子
These are our kids we're talking about.
我有另一個辦法
I can think of one other option.
弗蘭克
Frank.
都會好起來的  帕姆
Everything's gonna be okay, Pam.
我們很快就讓你回家陪家人
We're, we're gonna get you home to your family real soon.
好了  把門關上
We're good, close the door.
董事會非常清楚你為學校
The board is very aware of how hard you worked
為羅斯林  為他們的孩子付出了多少努力
for the schools, for Roslyn, for their kids.
他們知道你一直是得力干將
They know what an asset you've been, and, um...
所以他們明白這是怎麼回事
that is why they see this for-for what it is.
一時糊塗
A lapse in judgment.
鑒於此  他們決定
And in light of that, they're opting
不提出指控  也不報警
not to press charges or involve the police.
謝謝  謝謝你們大家
Thank you, thank you. All of you.
你要全額賠償學校
So you'll make full restitution to the school
二十五萬美元
at the sum of $250,000.
二十五萬  全額賠償  沒問題
250, full... full restitution, of course.
我會想辦法的
I'll, I'll make it happen.
然後你要完成本周的工作
And then you'll finish out the work week
並低調辭職
and resign quietly.
等一下
Wait.
-什麼  -明白嗎
- What? - Okay.
明天一早你要
Tomorrow morning, you'll surrender
把管理執照交給董事會
your administrators license to the board
簽署一份保密協議  承諾...
and you'll sign an NDA committing...
弗蘭克  弗蘭克  我不明白這是怎麼回事
Frank, Frank, I don't... I don't understand what's happening.
我不明白  你在說什麼...
I don't understand this. Why are you...
你偷了學校的錢  帕姆
You stole from the schools, Pam.
偷了納稅人的錢
From, from the taxpayers.
偷了我們應該服務的孩子的錢
From, from the kids we're supposed to serve.
這種...
I mean, this...
這種行為不只是不道德了
kind of behavior goes beyond the bounds of immoral.
是殘酷
It, it's, it's cruel, it's...
簡直令人髮指  甚至可以說是精神病
It's heinous. It's, it's sociopathic, even.
什麼  精神病
Sociopathic, what?
無恥的利己主義
The shameless self-interest.
不穩定的性格
The, the, the unstable personality.
張揚的婚姻鬧劇
The parade of rotten marriages, it...
弗蘭克
Frank.
你需要幫助  帕姆
Look, you need help, Pam.
真正的醫療幫助
Real medical help.
你病了
You're a sick woman.
我們很擔心你  帕姆
We're concerned about you, Pam.
我
I am...
我病了
I'm a sick woman.
我
I'm...
為我的行為感到羞恥  為我自己感到羞恥
I'm ashamed of my actions. I'm ashamed of myself. I'm...
我沒有任何借口
There's no excuse for it.
精神病算是借口
Well, the sociopathy.
-好吧  鮑勃  -是的
- Yeah, Bob, the... - Yeah.
好的
Okay.
我們明天一早就把一切安排好
We'll make all the arrangements first thing tomorrow morning.
好的  當然
Yeah, of course.
各位晚安
Good night, all.
比我想的要順利
Well, that went better than I thought.
你救了我們  弗蘭克
You saved our ass, Frank.
-天啊  是的  -謝謝你
- Oh, God, yeah. - Thank you.
是啊
Yeah.
帕姆·格盧金
剛剛是搞什麼鬼
What the hell was that?
你能聽到嗎
I... can you hear me?
弗蘭克
Frank?
好吧
Okay.
我只是想...
I'm just, I'm just trying to...
我只是想搞清楚情況
I'm trying to wrap my head around this.
我沒想到你會打來
I wasn't sure you were gonna call.
你還好嗎
Is everything okay?
嗯  抱歉  我...
Yeah, sorry, I, um...
只是想聽聽你的聲音
just wanted to hear your voice.
-他在哪  -帕姆
- Where is he? - Pam.
-他在哪  -帕姆  先...
- Where is he? - Pam, just...
-先坐下再說  -不  我要跟吉米說話
- Just sit down for a second. - No, I wanna talk to Jimmy.
-他在哪  -先坐下來再說
- Where is he? - Just sit down for a little bit.
他在這屋嗎  不  他在他臥室  是不是
Is he in this room? No, he's in his bedroom, isn't he?
-先...  -別碰我
- Just... - Don't touch me.
-別碰我  -行
- Don't touch me! - All right!
媽
Hey, Ma.
"媽"
Hi, Ma?
-帕姆姑媽  -滾出我的房子  吉米
- Hey, Aunt Pam! - Get outta my house, Jimmy!
-帕姆  -我不想讓你住這
- Pam! - I don't want you here anymore.
-滾出去  -帕姆
- Get the hell out! - Pam.
-我再也不想看見你這張臉了  -帕姆  停
- I don't wanna see your face anymore. - Pam, stop it.
-住口  你不是真心的  -怎麼了
- Stop it, you don't mean it. - Hey, what's going on?
你不是真心的  她不是真心的  吉姆
You don't mean it. She doesn't mean it, Jim.
-她根本不是真心那麼說的  -怎麼回事
- She doesn't mean one word of it. - What's going on?
你媽媽今天丟了工作
Your mother lost her job today.
不是我的工作  霍華德  我的事業
Yeah, not my job, Howard. My career.
我不懂  你不能在其它學校
I don't get it, can't you just get a different job
找份其它工作嗎
at another school?
他們要沒收我的執照
They're taking my license.
媽媽  你做了什麼
Mom, what did you do?
我拿了他們的錢
I took money from them.
對  我偷錢  我們都偷了
Yeah, I stole. We all did.
好了  你們先回各自房間
Okay, look, just go back to your rooms, please.
-沒錯  -讓我和你媽媽談談
- Yeah. - Please let me talk to your mother.
你的車  你的衣服
Your car, your clothes.
這房子  另一個房子
This house, the other houses.
-你在說什麼  -你不想去州立學校
- What are you talking about? - You didn't want state school.
你想去上私立大學
You wanted private college.
我希望你對我滿意
I wanted you to be happy with me.
帕姆  帕姆  沒事的
Pam, Pam, listen. It's okay.
我們能給你在經銷店找個工作  好嗎
We'll get you a job down at the dealership, okay?
對  他們要招個新前台小姐
Yeah, yeah, they're looking for a new girl at the front desk.
-做秘書嗎  -不不
- Like a secretary? - No, no.
不  不是秘書
Not, not as... not like a secretary.
你總會找到工作的  我只是說
You'll find something. I'm just saying...
-我有學位  -我懂
- I have degrees. - I know.
我上了那麼多年學才拿到學位
I went to school for years to get degrees.
我開過校車  我做過速記
I drove the bus. I did the steno pool.
-該做的我都做了  -聽我說  帕姆
- I did everything I had to. - Listen to me, Pam.
-聽我說  -我要吐了
- Listen to me. - I'm gonna be sick.
你是我認識的最聰明的女人
You are the smartest woman I have ever known.
我們會度過這個困難
We're gonna get through this and you're gonna
你會重振旗鼓的
land on your feet, you will.
過來
Come here.
-霍華德  -我懂
- Howard. - I know.
我懂
I know.
羅斯林高中
格盧金夫人
Mrs. Gluckin.
我想問下
I was just wondering.
能再給我一次地下室的鑰匙嗎
Could I get the key to the basement again?
我就想再查一點東西
I just want to look up a few more things.
你要做什麼  瑞秋
What's this for, Rachel?
我想確認一些東西
Just for some stuff I wanted to verify.
我可以回答你的問題
I can answer your questions.
好吧
Okay, well...
我算了下  天橋項目似乎
I did the math, and it looks like the SkyWalk
總共要花費八百萬美元
is gonna end up costing around eight million dollars.
-七百五十萬  當然  -對
- Seven-five, sure. - Right.
我們似乎要在美觀問題上
It just seems like a lot of our resources
投入大量資源
to be spending on cosmetics.
美觀  大家都喜歡天橋
Cosmetics? People love the SkyWalk.
《山峰燈塔》喜歡天橋項目
"The Beacon" loves the SkyWalk.
你們發起了投票
There was that nice poll you guys did.
對
Right.
但這所高中的天花板還在漏水
But the ceilings at the high school are still leaking.
有一些教室被迫關閉
I mean, some of the classrooms had to get shut down.
那麼你也許應該在
Sounds like you should bring that up
學生會上提起這個
with your student government.
還有那個披薩烤箱
There was also the pizza oven.
-什麼  -我在費用報表
- What? - I saw a line item
看到了一行披薩烤爐的支出記錄
in the expense reports for a pizza oven.
但我之後問了食堂的寶拉
But then I asked Paula in the cafeteria
她說她完全不知道有這回事
and she said she knew nothing about it.
別說了
Just stop it.
很抱歉我得告訴你這個
I am sorry to be the one to tell you this,
但沒人對你們有所隱瞞  好嗎
but no one is keeping anything from you, okay?
相反  我們每天天一亮就來這
On the contrary, we come in here every day
是因為我們關心你們
at the crack of dawn because we care.
我們希望能給你們提供
We care about providing you
良好的高質量教育  因為我們是好人
with a proper quality education because we're good people.
因為我們希望你們能過上好日子
Because we want you to have a good life.
好嗎
Okay?
好
Okay.
但消費記錄仍然屬於公開數據
The individual purchase orders are still public record, though.
給
Here you go.
謝謝
Thank you.
另外瑞秋
Oh, and Rachel.
那個披薩烤箱的事你說對了
You were right about that pizza oven.
不是買給高中的
It didn't go to the high school
因為我們是給初中買的
because we bought it for the middle school.
對  他們吃了好幾天披薩了
Yeah, they have pizza for days down there.
你也去吃一塊
Go get yourself a slice.
早安
Morning.
-你好  -瑞秋
- Hi. - Oh, hey, Rachel.
塔索內博士  帕姆·格盧金狀態不太好
Dr. Tassone, Pam Gluckin's in a bit of a state.
我早上很忙
Yeah, I have a very busy morning.
跟她說我沒時間見她  早安
Just tell her I can't. Good morning.
弗蘭克  弗蘭克  弗蘭克
Frank, Frank, Frank!
弗蘭...
Fra...
抱歉  塔索內博士今早很忙
I'm sorry, Dr. Tassone's very busy this morning.
別擋道  瑪麗·安
Get out of my way, Mary Ann.
-帕姆  帕姆  -拜託
- Pam, Pam. - Please.
算了  沒事
You know what? It's fine.
什麼事都沒有
Everything's fine.
這是我留給他的離職談話
My exit interview for him.
塔索內博士
Hey, Dr. Tassone.
瑪麗·安說你想見我
Mary Ann said you wanted to see me?
對  請坐
Yes, yes. Uh, take a seat.
把門關上
Just close the door behind you there.
我想
So, I think maybe
我們該討論一下
it is time that we talked about your value
你在這堛漱u作價值了
in this workplace.
我
I, uh...
-這不是  -不  請安心
- This isn't... - No, rest assured,
我們都希望你能在這堥得成功
we all want you to succeed here.
所以
Which is...
我們希望能把你調職到
Which is why we would like to transition you
我們的特殊事務部
to our special utilities department.
先生
Sir, um...
我還以為我在這媟F得不錯
you know, I just thought I was a really good fit up here.
當然了  我們只是換換崗
Oh, yeah, no, no, no. We're just doing some shuffling
那邊真的缺個人手
and we could really use an extra hand down there.
好嗎
Okay?
帕姆留下的職位如何  我想或許
What about Pam's old job? You know, I thought maybe, uh,
我能當個經理之類的
you know, like a manager, maybe I could be...
也許我能做那個
Maybe I could be right for that.
實際上  菲利普·梅茨格
Yeah, well, actually, Philip Metzger's
要繼任為臨時商務經理
gonna be stepping in as the interim business manager.
-審計員菲爾  -對  對
- Phil the auditor? - Yeah, yeah.
在我們找到正式替代帕姆的職員之前
I mean, until we can find a more permanent replacement for Pam.
但
But...
他能上任我們都很激動
we're pretty excited about him.
我想我該
I think that I should, uh...
我想
think, um...
我知道你們對帕姆做了什麼
I know what you all did to Pam.
我可以  你懂的  我可以
And I could, you know, I could...
告訴別人
maybe tell people.
抱歉  請稍等  抱歉打斷一下
Sorry, hold on a second. I'm so sorry to interrupt.
我注意到了你戴的項鏈
I just noticed that necklace you have on.
襯托出了你的眼睛
How it really complements your eyes.
-謝謝  -項鏈
- Thank you. - It's, uh,
是新的  不是嗎
yeah, that's, that's new, isn't it?
我以前應該沒見你戴過
I don't think I've seen you wearing it around before.
對  我想是這樣
Yeah, I thought so. Yeah. I've got...
我對這些東西比較敏銳
I got sort of an eye for these things, I don't know.
你說呢
So, um, what do you think?
是在梅西百貨買的呢
Is that... is that a Macy's purchase or are we talking
還是在羅德與泰勒百貨買的
Lord & Taylor collection?
你之前說特殊事務部
Special utilities, you said?
對  是這樣
Yeah, I think so.
好  謝謝  珍
Okay, thanks, Jen.
這堛犖諯垢f不是我
瑪麗·安  能給我來一杯新的那種咖啡嗎
Mary Ann, can I get a cup of that new coffee in here?
洛可  你真煩人
Rocco, you're so annoying.
別擋路
Get out of the way.
去
Go.
-媽  -就是我
- Mom! - This is she.
不
No.
等等  什麼
Wait, what?
是  謝謝  請別再打來了
Yeah, thank you. Please don't call here again.
-是誰  -一個學生
- Who was that? - That was a student.
他們想把時裝秀的收益捐贈出來
They want to donate the fashion show proceeds
幫助我治病
to help pay for my medical expenses.
-但你沒生病  -別吃那個
- But you're not sick. - Don't eat that.
我們要把那些還回去
We're returning them.
帕姆  到底怎麼回事
Pam, what the hell is going on?
山峰燈塔
備受喜愛的行政員工突然因重病辭職
好
Okay, uh...
首先  我們想花點時間
first off, we want to take a moment
向帕梅拉·格盧金致敬
to acknowledge Pamela Gluckin.
我們掛念她  以及她的家人
Our hearts go out to her and her entire family
我們希望她能迅速痊癒
and we wish her a safe and speedy recovery, yeah.
好  現在
Okay, all right, now.
該說有意思的事了
Onto the fun stuff.
2003年FIHS提前錄取數據
哥倫比亞
達特茅斯
布朗
哈佛
耶魯
普林斯頓
看看這些數據
Look at these numbers, folks.
這是我們見過的
These are the best early decision numbers
最出色的提前錄取數據
that we've ever seen.
對
Yeah.
為自己來點掌聲
Give yourselves a round of applause.
羅斯林學區行政董事自由聯合會
為您奉上節日祝福
祝您度過溫暖  愉快  其樂融融的假期
節日快樂
弗蘭克·塔索內
七
Seven.
六
Six.
五
Five.
瑞秋  你那篇
Hey, Rachel, um, where's the article
癌癥公益時裝秀的稿子在哪
on the Cancer Benefit Fashion Show?
我明天交給你
I'll get that to you tomorrow.
但我們明天就要刊印了
But we go to print tomorrow.
好  我今晚給你
Okay, I'll have it tonight.
如果你想成為報社一員
Look, if you wanna be a part of the paper,
你就得作為報社一員行動
you gotta be a part of the paper.
我要遲到了
Look, I'm gonna be late.
瑞秋  瑞秋
Rachel. Rachel!
-見鬼  -老天
- Shit. - Oh, my God.
-抱歉  見鬼  -不是吧
- Sorry, shit. - Seriously?
這是什麼
What is this?
那是私人項目  與你無關
It's just a personal project. None of your business.
很抱歉我對你那麼強硬
Look, I'm sorry for being a hard-ass.
我知道你家堨X了很多事
I know you're going through a lot at home.
你什麼意思
What's that supposed to mean?
就是你爸爸的那些事情
You know, just everything with your dad.
他的什麼事
Yeah, what about him?
家長之間會聊天
I mean, the parents talk to each other.
我聽說他工作上不順利
I know that some shit happened at work.
你什麼都不懂
You don't know anything.
操  蕾切爾
Fuck, Rachel.
小蕾
Rach?
-吃晚飯了  -好的
- Dinner. - Okay.
這是什麼
What's all this?
我做的調查
Research.
這些是學區的發票
These are invoices from the school district.
學區花了一百多萬
The school district invoiced over a million dollars
買實驗室設備
in lab equipment?
這只是一個供應商的
And that's just one supplier.
你想過打給這家公司嗎
You thought about calling this company?
天  我要錯過我的航班了
Oh, God, I'm gonna miss my flight.
那就再待一天吧
Not if you stay another day.
你知道我不能留下
You know I can't do that.
你可以在這塈鉽茪u作
You could get a job here.
克拉克縣也有一些學校
There are schools in Clark County.
當然  但有好的嗎
Sure, but good ones?
在你去之前羅斯林算好的嗎
Was Roslyn any good before you?
請問是尤寧代爾的冠軍製品嗎
Hi, is this Champion Products in Uniondale?
-是的  -你好  我叫蕾切爾
- Yes, it is. - Hi, my name is Rachel.
我想向您咨詢幾筆開銷
I was just hoping to ask you about a series of charges.
好的  謝謝你的查證  菲利斯
Okay, yes, yes. Thank you for verifying, Felice.
你幫了很大的忙
You've been a huge help.
-好的  -謝謝  再見
- Yeah. - Thank you, bye-bye.
沒錯
That's right.
我可以等
Yeah, I can hold.
這堿O貝爾莫爾精品汽車  我是霍華德
Bellmore Fine Auto, this is Howard.
抱歉  貝爾莫爾精品汽車
I'm sorry. Bellmore Fine Auto?
我看這個號碼登記的是HG咨詢公司
I had this number listed as an H. G. Consulting.
怎麼了
What's the matter?
沒事  我只是累了
Oh, nothing, I'm just, just tired.
發票給我吧
I'll take those invoices.
下一個是言辭力量科技公司
Next up is WordPower Tech.
他們給學區開了八十萬美元的發票
Now, they billed the school district $800,000
但沒人知道他們是誰
but no one has any idea who they are.
而且他們一直如此
And they're consistent.
過去十年堨L們年年都開發票
They've billed every year for the past ten.
這家登記在托馬斯·提吉羅名下
Yeah, the company's registered to Thomas Tuggiero
位於曼哈頓的公司
with an address in Manhattan.
我試著打過去  但號碼已經停用了
I tried calling but the number is disconnected.
托馬斯·提吉羅
公園大道5575號1607室
紐約州紐約市
這個現在先打個問號
We're gonna leave that one a question mark for right now
因為下一個是波爾多辦公用品
because the next one I've got is Porto Office Supplies.
我找不到任何...
Now, I can't find any...
紐約  B站台
怎麼  你忘帶鑰匙了嗎
What, did you forget your key?
你好
Hello.
有什麼事嗎
Can I help you with something?
這堿O不是
Is this...
我
I'm...
我在做民意調查
I'm canvassing.
為誰做
For who?
是...
It's...
我找錯公寓了
I'm, I have the wrong apartment.
你回來了
You're back.
我回來了  謝謝
I'm back. Hey, thanks.
晚餐吃什麼
Hey, what's for dinner?
三文魚
Salmon.
怎麼了
What's the matter?
只是工作的事  抱歉
Oh, it's just work. Sorry.
三文魚有點柴
The salmon's a little dry.
很好吃
It's great.
我能看出你在撒謊
I can tell when you're lying.
可能是有點柴
A little dry, maybe.
但粗麥粉真是絕味
The couscous, though, is a small masterpiece.
謝謝誇獎
Oh, well, thank you very much.
在奧馬哈如何
How was Omaha?
無聊  無聊透頂
Dull. Dull as all hell.
於是
So...
我夾在道格和喬之間
So I'm sitting there sandwiched between Doug and Joe
會議中心沒開空調
and there's no A/C in the conference center
你能想像得到那股臭味
so you can imagine the smell while they...
天啊
Oh, God.
他們花幾個小時聊理工科項目和國家補助
...talked for hours about STEM programs and state aid.
那真是
It was, oh, yeah.
-那真是糟透了  -聽起來像個噩夢
- It was, it was a riot. - Oh, sounds like a nightmare.
或許下次我該一起去
Maybe I'll come along next time.
給你擋一擋
As a buffer.
我絕不會讓你去受那種罪
I would never subject you to that.
你有佐證的文件嗎
Okay, you have documents to back this up?
多年來給供應商的付款記錄
Years' worth of supposed payments to vendors
和供應商未收到錢的證明
and confirmation they were never received.
這堶惘釭漱膝q甚至不存在
Some of these companies, they don't even exist.
你不能確定這點
Well, no, you don't know that.
我的意思是你確定嗎
I mean, you know that for sure, right?
言辭力量科技公司
WordPower Tech.
他們給學區開過近百萬美元的發票
They've billed the district almost a million dollars
但沒人知道它
and no one knows anything.
-因為它並不存在  -好吧
- Because it isn't anything. - Okay.
那是上東區的一間私人公寓
It is a private apartment on the upper East Side.
-是  但那不能  -我們的主管
- Yes, but that doesn't... - And our superintendent
-有那堛瘋_匙  -完全證明公司是假的
- has the key. - ...necessarily mean that it's fake.
承認吧  尼克  你明白的
Come on, Nick, you know what this is.
如果他沒有舉報  那就是詐騙
If he hasn't reported this, it's fraud.
他在寫我的大學推薦信
He's writing my college recommendation letter.
操  操  操他媽的
Fuck, fuck, god damn it.
我們現在在說什麼啊
What are we even talking about right now?
你確定嗎  你百分百確定
Are you sure? Are you sure, sure, sure
要這麼做嗎
you actually wanna do this?
預算調查揭露重大瀆職嫌疑
我可以坐這兒嗎
Mind if I join you?
千萬別讓你的醫生發現
Don't ever let a doctor find out
你膽固醇過高  蕾切爾
you have high cholesterol, Rachel.
他們會逼你做很可怕的事情
They'll make you do the most horrible things.
那麼
So.
關於昨天
About yesterday.
-那是  -你在那幹什麼
- That was... - What were you doing there?
我沒有生氣
I'm not upset.
但你一定要實話實說
But it is very important that you be honest.
我在調查學校承包商的
I was following up on the listed address
登記地址
for a school contractor.
你為什麼要做這些
Why were you doing that?
那是公開記錄  任何人都可以花時間
It's public record. Anyone could take the time...
我沒問你那是不是公開記錄
I didn't ask you if it was public record.
我問你為什麼
I... I just asked you why.
是為了我在寫的文章
It's for something I'm writing.
我覺得你很有潛力
I think you have real potential.
-塔索內博士  -不  我是認真的
- Dr. Tassone... - No, I'm serious.
我讀過你所有的報道
I, I read all your bylines.
你比去年九月進步了很多
You've come such a long way since past September.
你的自信和強大的能力
Your confidence, strength of ability.
-謝謝  -你的前途非常光明
- Thank you. - No, you have a tremendous future ahead of you,
真的  蕾切爾
Rachel, you do.
但是
But...
你還是太年輕
You're still young, too.
這也是為什麼你要知道  我是認真的
Which is why you need to know, and I mean this,
如果你公開了
if you go public...
一些你不完全瞭解的事情
with something you don't fully understand,
你會自食其果的
it'll, it'll come back on you hard.
我不知道
I don't know, I...
我想這主要是我們的錯
I guess it's our fault, mainly.
我們試圖創造一個安全的環境  讓學生們
We try to create a safe environment for students to...
去挑戰  冒險  犯錯  成長
challenge, take risks, make mistakes, grow.
但如果你犯了這個錯誤
But this mistake, if you make it,
我們無法保護你
we will not be able to protect you.
我不行  你的老師們不行  因為這會改變一切
Not me, not your teachers. Because it'll change everything.
很多無辜的人會受到傷害
And a lot of innocent people will get hurt.
明白嗎
Right?
我的意思是  這些調查
I mean, these kinds of inquiries
就像引爆一枚手榴彈
are, are... are like setting off a grenade.
瘋狂追求真相會造成後果
There's fallout in the pursuit. In the frenzy.
會殃及池魚
There's collateral damage.
對吧
Right...
你一定清楚這些
You must know all about that.
雖然不完美  但有成效
It's not perfect, but it works.
我們現有的制度很有成效
What we have here works.
我希望我們能保持下去
I hope we can keep it that way.
我們來看看這個  蕾切爾
All right, let's get into it. Uh, Rachel.
蕾切爾
Hey, Rachel.
蕾切爾  你在聽課嗎
Rachel, are you still with us?
我在聽
Yeah, yeah, I'm here.
-抱歉  -好
- Sorry. - All right.
第四題
Question number four,
鉀的符號是什麼
what is the symbol for potassium?
有人知道嗎
Anybody?
請進
Yeah.
弗蘭克
Hey, Frank.
上周我做了更深入的調查
I've been doing some more digging over the past week.
我有點擔心
I'm... concerned...
我所發現的東西
with what I found.
過來說
Okay, come in.
我們現在沒有收據
Look, now we don't have receipts,
但有一些供應商  他們
but some of these vendors, they're...
帕姆的事不只是我們起初認為的
this Pam thing isn't a question of $250,000
二十五美元的問題
like we'd initially thought.
好吧
Well, okay, uh,
你估計大概有多少
do you have any sense of what the number might be?
五十萬
I mean, are we talking 500?
一百萬
Are we talking a million?
菲爾  說說吧  我很難
I mean, Phil, work with me. I can't do anything but just...
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know, I don't know.
你不知道  好吧
You don't... okay, fine. So...
那就算清楚  好嗎
figure it out, all right?
發揮你的數字專長
Work your numbers magic and then,
就我們兩人把這事辦妥了  好嗎
let's the two of us deal with it from there, okay?
謝謝  菲爾
Thanks, Phil.
還有其他事
Well, there's something else.
寒假期間飛往倫敦希思羅機場的機票
A flight to London, Heathrow, over winter break...
-發票開給  -那是我的
- ...billed to... - Yeah, that's me.
機票是買給我的  去參加佩爾會議
That flight was for me, for the Pell Conference.
你知道的
You knew about the Pell.
噴氣式飛機的頭等艙
First class, Concorde jet.
不是我訂的機票  那都是傑妮的工作
I don't book the flights. That's always been Jenny's job.
-即使是我訂的  -費用是兩個座位的
- But look, even if I had... - The charge is for two seats.
頭等艙兩個並排的座位
Two seats side by side in first.
一張單程票五千美元
It's $5,000 each way per ticket.
總共兩萬美元
It's $20,000.
這應該是弄錯了
Yeah, well, that sounds like a mistake.
我打給了航空公司
You know, I called the airline.
凱爾·孔特雷拉是誰
Who's Kyle Contreras?
好吧
Okay, okay.
你要這麼耍我嗎
So that's how you wanna play it.
什麼  不  我不是耍你
What, no. I'm not playing...
真是厚顏無恥
I mean, the audacity.
花了六個月
Coming from the man who spent six months
偽造我們的記錄來掩蓋
falsifying our records to mask his own negligence
在對學校的受信責任上的失職
of fiduciary duty to the school.
等等  不是  不是這樣的
Wait a second, that's not what, that's not what's going on.
不是嗎
No, no?
帕姆的事本不該發生  對吧
Pam didn't have to happen, right?
你本可以阻止的  你是審計
You could have prevented that. You're the auditor.
人家花錢雇你幹什麼
The people here pay you for what?
你想走就走  想玩戲劇就玩戲劇
So you can go off and do your community theater
我們學校的賬本都不用管的嗎
instead of taking care of our school's books?
對  對
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
指手畫腳我也會  菲爾
Oh, I can point fingers too, Phil.
但是我想我們看法是一致的
Right, but I think we both agree that
這不過是浪費我們的時間而已
that wouldn't be a very productive use of our time.
-可是  -菲爾
- But... - Phil.
你要不要去做你的事
Are you gonna do your job,
還是要我把海韋希本人叫過來
or do I have to call Hevesi in here himself
讓他替你把工作做了
to come and do it for you?
因為我現在就能給他打電話
Because I will call him right now.
我會處理的
I will deal with it.
很抱歉我提起這件事  我不該提的
I'm sorry that I brought it up. I shouldn't have.
是  太對了  你不該提的
Yeah, damn right you shouldn't have.
你不會再聽到這事了
You won't hear about it again.
很好
Good.
出去
Get out of here.
爸  我能問你件事嗎
Hey, Dad, can I ask you something?
你不想回答也可以
And you don't have to answer if you don't want to.
可以啊  你隨便問
Yeah, you can ask me anything.
我知道當時你說過
I mean, I know what you had said at, at the time,
那時候
when, um,
發生的那些事
all that stuff was happening.
內幕交易
The insider trading.
你真的不知情嗎
Did you really not know?
你是不是想問我有沒有參與其中
Are you asking me if I was a part of it?
我沒有參與
No, I wasn't.
任何時候都沒有參與  我向你保證
Not at any point in time, I promise you.
但是
But, uh...
你要理解
You gotta understand,
我整個職業生涯都跟那些人打交道
those were guys that I had come up with my entire career.
你和尼爾週末就跟他們的孩子玩
Guys whose kids you and Neil played with on the weekends.
他們有家庭  他們都是好人
Guys with families. They were good people.
長遠來看  一切都會過去的
And it was all gonna even out in the long run.
誰會在乎呢
So who cares?
我當時什麼都沒說
I didn't say anything.
我本來可以說的
I could have.
但是我沒說
But I didn't.
這是我要背的包袱
And that's something I live with.
早
Morning.
記錄顯示  多年可疑經費支出始於高層
鮑勃
Bob...
你讓我成為這個地區的公眾人物
you had me serve as the public face of this district,
代表繁榮的形象
an image that reflects prosperity.
我知道出了這樣的事情很糟糕
Okay, I know it might look bad all laid out like that
但是試試從我的角度看問題
but try and see this from my point of view.
這就是我做的工作
This is me doing the job I was hired for.
皺巴巴的西裝是一回事
A wrinkled suit. Yeah, okay, that's one thing.
這完全是另一回事
This is something else entirely.
不不不  我的僱傭合同有一項條款
No, no, no, my employment contract
允許我在履行職責所需的
has a clause that allows me full discretion
所有費用上
on all charges necessary and proper
-有充分的自由裁量權  -這點我知道
- to the discharge of my duties. - I know that.
你的僱傭合同是我擬的
I wrote your employment contract.
關鍵詞就是這個"自由裁量權"
The key word there was "discretion."
-鮑勃  你沒聽我說  -我聽得很清楚
- Bob, you're not hearing me. - I'm hearing fine.
你花了三萬塊乾洗衣服
You spent $30,000 on dry cleaning.
好幾年累積的  是的
Over a number of years, yes, I did,
我會全部還上的
and I will pay it all back.
但我這麼做是為了學校
Right, but I did it for the good of the school.
不  你就是為了自己好看
No, you just... you wanted to look pretty.
拜託  弗蘭克
Come on, Frank.
如今這已經是公開的秘密了
It's practically, it's an open secret
你的行為舉止
nowadays with the way you're carrying on.
華麗的西裝  古龍水
The flashy suits, the cologne.
你做的整形
The shit that you're doing to your face.
他們都笑話你
They laugh at you.
你是我的人
You were my guy.
我帶你入伙的  我還替你辯解
I brought you in. I defended you.
現在我被你害慘了  我們都被你害慘了
Now, I'm compromised now. We all are.
因為
Because of, of...
你們這些人對我們做了什麼
What did you people do to us?
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
很多年前
So we were at dinner
我們一起吃晚飯
however many years ago.
不是什麼高檔餐廳  是...
Uh, it was nowhere fancy. It was...
貝爾大街上的一家披薩店
a pizza place on Bell Boulevard.
兩份希臘沙拉和一杯汽水
Two Greek salads and a fountain drink.
我弄錯了  不小心刷錯了卡
And I fucked up, I used the wrong card by accident.
二十美元
It's for $20.
然後我說  週一我會把錢還上的
And I said, I'd even it all out on Monday.
我會自掏腰包把錢還給學校
I'd reimburse the school out of pocket.
不論怎樣我們都要還
Whatever we had to do, you know.
週一到了  又過去了
Monday came and went.
沒人說一句話  沒人在乎
Nobody said anything. Nobody, nobody cared.
週二  刷了一個六十美分的硬麵包圈
On Tuesday, it was a 60 cent bagel.
鮑勃  如果...
Bob, if...
如果我想要錢
if I wanted the money...
我早就去華爾街了
I would have gone to Wall Street.
我會像你一樣
I'd be living in a big house
住在郊區的大房子  但是...
in the country estates like you, but...
我想要有所作為
I wanted to make a difference.
對吧
Right?
是的  我們都是  你看
I did, we did, look.
我們現在排名第四
We're number four.
我幫大家爭到了第四的位置
I got us all the way to number four.
我拿著教師水平的工資做到了
Right, and I did it on a glorified teacher's salary
而你和其他人卻從這個學區賺了幾百萬
while you and everyone else made millions off the district.
我幫大家爭到了第四
I got us to number four,
我會帶領大家爭到第一的
and I will get us to number one.
董事會召開了緊急會議
The board, we convened an emergency session.
我們要就十一月處理帕姆的情況
We're gonna make a public statement
向鎮上發表公開聲明
to the town about the way we handled Pam in November.
什麼  拜託  不行
What? Come on, no.
-是的  必須這樣  -不行  不行
- No, yes, that's how it has to be. - No, no.
現在不行  不要
Not now, no.
要等到預算投票通過才行
Not until the budget vote goes through.
就差幾天了  鮑勃  這個...
It's a few days away. Bob, it's...
鮑勃
Bob.
我還有辦法讓貝卡進哈佛
I can still get Becca into Harvard.
希望你能找到內心的安寧  弗蘭克
I hope you find peace, Frank.
-為什麼是孩子們  -請...
- Why are we hearing about this... - Please...
而不是你親自告訴我們
from our children and not from you?
-我們知道你們  -我們的錢到底在哪
- We know you're... - Where the hell's our money?
我們知道你們很生氣  也知道你們很憤怒
We know you're upset. We know you're angry.
但是我們不能...我們不能
But we cannot... we simply cannot afford
通過控制學校的預算
to hold our school's budget hostage
來妨礙你們孩子的教育
to place a filibuster on your children's education.
這是高層勾結
This is collusion at the highest level.
我們要求辭職
We demand resignations.
這樣沒用
This is not productive.
不不不  我理解你們的心情
No, no, no, no, I understand where this is coming from.
但是我會一一回答你們的問題
But I will answer each of your questions.
首先請允許我讀一下這份聲明
First, please just let me read this statement that I prepared.
你們都該進監獄
You all should be in prison!
夠了
Enough!
瑪麗·安  到底發生什麼了
Mary Ann, what the hell's going on?
瑪麗·安
Mary Ann?
海韋希今早打電話來了
Hevesi called this morning.
弗蘭克  你說過他永遠不會打電話來的
Frank, you said he would never call.
弗蘭克
Frank.
你好  塔索內博士
Hi, Dr. Tassone.
很高興能等到你
Oh, we're so glad we could catch you.
施魏策爾夫人  卡蘿爾  現在真不是時候
Uh, Ms. Schweitzer, uh, Carol, now's really not the best time.
拜託了  我們只佔用您一點時間
Please, please, we just need one minute of your attention.
查德有件事非常想和您分享
Chad has something that he would really like to share with you.
好吧  拜託  您能花一點時間
All right, please, why don't you just take a moment,
聽他讀完嗎
all right, and hear him out.
當然
Of course.
當然可以
Of course I will.
-好了嗎  -好吧
- Yeah? - Okay.
下午好  塔索內博士  您週末過得怎麼樣
Good afternoon, Dr. Tassone. How was your weekend?
希望您愉快  我今天想跟您談談
Good, I hope. I'd like to talk to you today
您管理的實驗班
about the OMNI program that you are running.
等等  我們去年秋天已經談過這件事了
Wait, I thought we already discussed the subject of OMNI last fall.
是的  米利措克讓他補考了
Oh, yeah, no, Militzok gave him the make-up test
但是她加大了難度來為難他
but she made it harder to spite him.
沒有哪個三年級學生能通過那個考試
And no third grader could pass that test.
好的  我想我得調查一下
All right, well, I guess I'll just have to look into it.
查德  你給塔索內博士讀完吧
Chad, why don't you just finish reading for Dr. Tassone?
-好的  -嗯
- Okay. - Uh-huh.
我真心希望您能考慮讓我
I very much hope that you will still consider me
進這個實驗班
for this amazing program.
我相信我很聰明  因此可以
I believe I am very bright and could benefit
從加...
from learning thusly at an ack...
-加...  -把那個念出來
- ack... - Okay, sound that out.
加...加...
acc... acc...
-加速  -嗯  是的
- Accelerated? - Mm-hmm, that's right.
塔索內博士  你聽到塔索內博士說的了
Dr. Tassone. You hear what Dr. Tassone said?
好的  從這段開頭再來一遍
Okay, all right, start again from the beginning of the paragraph.
下午好  塔索內博士  您週末過得怎麼樣
Good afternoon, Dr. Tassone. How was your weekend?
-我希望您愉快  -不不不  就跳到
- Good, I hope. - Oh, no, no, let's, let's skip
有問題的那個句子  查德
to that trouble sentence there, Chad.
也行  好吧  慢慢來
That's okay. All right, yeah, take your time.
從...
From...
我相信我很聰明  因此可以
I believe I am very bright and could benefit
從加...
from learning thusly at an ack...
-加速  -"加組"
- Accelerated. - "Ackselated"?
加速
Accelerated.
-"加足"  -加  速
- "Arrelicated"? - Ac-celerated.
好吧
Okay.
你喜歡賽車嗎  查德
Do you like race cars, Chad?
喜歡嗎  好的
Yeah? Okay.
假設你坐在賽車
Let's say you're in a racecar.
好了  這樣  不用那個了
All right, here, you don't need that.
你坐在賽車
You're in a racecar.
處於印第安納波利斯五百英里大獎賽的領先位置
First place at the Indy 500
世界上所有的贊助商都來了
with, with all the sponsorships in the world.
風吹過你的頭髮  你感覺很棒
The wind is in your hair and you're feeling just great,
突然間  你感到後面有東西追上來
and all of a sudden, you feel this thing behind you
快碰上你的擋泥板
digging into your fender,
然後你朝後視鏡一看
and you look into the mirror, right.
有一個掛鉤
And there's this hook.
你的擋泥板上有個掛鉤
There's a hook in your fender dug in real good,
掛鉤上綁著一條長長的金屬繩
and it's connected to a... a long metal rope
繩子的末端
and at the end of that rope
綁著巨大的五噸重的煤渣塊
is, well, it's a massive five-ton cinder block.
知道吧  查德  對吧
Okay, Chad? All right?
你的任務是開車
So your job is driving.
你是達勒·恩哈德  後面是煤渣塊
You're Dale Earnhardt and here's this cinder block,
旁邊所有的車飛奔而過
and all the other cars are soaring past you and
你從第一位掉到了最後一位
you've gone from first to last place
你就不停地想
and you keep thinking to yourself,
我到底要怎麼做才能甩掉後面這玩意
"What the hell do I have to do to get this thing off my back?"
好的  我告訴你  查德  很簡單
Well, I'll tell you, Chad. It's real simple.
你的腳就使勁踩油門
You just put your foot on the gas real hard
你加快速度
and you accelerate,
你加快速度  繩子就會斷成兩截
you accelerate so fast that rope snaps in two,
煤渣就爆了
the cinder block explodes,
跟我一起說  查德
and just say it with me, Chad.
加速  加速  加速
Accelerate. Accelerate. Accelerate.
-加速  -對了
- Accelerate? - Yes.
-好了  -很好
- Okay. - Yes!
你腦子有問題吧
What, what is your problem, huh?
我有問題
My problem?
你就是我的問題
My problem is you.
卡蘿爾  是你這種
Carol, it's, it's, it's the people who
像溜賽馬一樣拿孩子攀比的人
who trot their poor children out like racehorses at Belmont.
-你說什麼  -是你這種
- Excuse me? - Who derive some perverse joy
通過支使我們獲取變態滿足感的人
out of treating us like low-level service reps.
-夠了  -你還記得坐在你身邊
- Okay... - I mean, do you remember the teachers who sat with you,
握著你的手
who held you by the hand,
-教你加法的老師嗎  -別說了
- who taught you to add. - No.
還有減法  帶你讀《了不起的蓋茨比》
And subtract, or showed you Gatsby,
塞林格的書  甚至是《殺死一隻知更鳥》
Salinger for the first time. "Mockingbird," even.
你忘了他們的名字嗎
Do, do their names escape you?
-他們長什麼樣  -夠了
- Are their faces a blur? - Okay.
不  你給我聽好
No, you listen to me!
你不想把我們當人對待
You don't wanna see us as people
因為那對你來說不夠便利
because that is not convenient for you.
你用完了就把我們拋到腦後
You just leave us behind at will.
再也想不起來
Never think about us again.
懂嗎  你可能會忘  但我們不會
All right, you might forget, but we don't.
我們永遠不會忘
We never forget, ever.
他怎麼了
What's wrong with him?
我也不知道
You know what, I don't know.
我覺得沒怎麼
I don't think anything's wrong.
我們去吃點東西  然後就回家  好嗎
We're gonna get some food and we're gonna go home, okay?
好
All right.
你應該感到羞恥
You should be ashamed of yourself.
在佛州和漢普敦的兩處海濱別墅
Two beach front homes in Florida and the Hamptons.
五輛雅馬哈水上摩托  豪車
Five Yamaha Jet-Skis. Luxury cars.
去巴西  波多黎各  夏威夷度假
Vacations to Brazil, Puerto Rico, Hawaii.
電子產品  首飾和藝術品
Electronics, jewelry and artwork.
狗糧
Dog food.
我的律師到了嗎
Is my lawyer here yet?
你要把牢底坐穿了  帕姆
You're going away for a long time, Pam.
而且不只是你
And not just you.
我們有足夠的證據起訴你全家
We've got enough here to indict the whole family.
別把他們扯進來
Don't you talk about them.
尤其是可憐的吉姆
And poor Jim especially.
剛剛振作起來
Just gettin' back on his feet and all.
你知道這年頭有前科的人
You have any idea what the job market looks like
找工作有多難嗎
these days for ex-cons?
這樣吧
You know...
也許你還來得及救他們
it may not be too late for you to save them.
救你兒子
Save your son.
你來做什麼
What are you doing here?
我想見你了
I wanted to see you.
你不用上班嗎
You don't have work?
我辭職了
I quit.
-什麼時候  -就今天
- When? - Today.
我就...
I just...
直接上了飛機  現在我來了
just got on a plane and now I'm here.
我再也不走了
And I... I'm not leaving again.
來跳舞
Dance.
-來跟我跳舞  弗蘭克  -不  不要
- Dance with me, Frank. - No, no.
跳一會  來吧
A little move, come on.
來嘛
Come on.
請
Please.
這就對了
There we go.
酒放下  酒放下
Drink down, drink down.
好了
Okay.
什麼
What?
-動起來  動起來  -不要
- Shake it up, shake it. - No.
來嘛
Come on!
特殊事務部
沒必要當著他們的面
They don't need to watch.
拿索郡警察
櫃子最上面的抽屜埵酗T萬美元
There's $30,000 in the top drawer of the dresser.
什麼
What?
如果你省著花  能撐一年
Okay, if you're careful, you can make it last a year.
你說什麼呢
What are you talking about?
你的天賦獨一無二
What you've got in you is so special
你永遠不能讓任何人奪走它
that you can't ever, ever let anyone take it away from you
或者利用它
or exploit it.
什麼...
What the hell...
你真的  真的...
You really, you really...
-搞什麼  -跟我在一起對你沒好處
- ...is happening right now? - You don't want me here.
你因紐約州的逮捕令被捕了
You're under arrest for a warrant out of the state of New York.
請下車
Please step out of the car.
弗蘭克  到底怎麼回事
Frank, what the hell is happening right now?
先生  把雙手放在儀表盤上
Sir, I need your hands on the dash.
弗蘭克  到底怎麼回事
Frank, what the hell is happening right now?
你不瞭解我
You don't know me.
-弗蘭克  -我不是好人
- Frank! - Okay, I'm no good.
這麼久以來
All this time
我一直在騙你  騙所有人
I've been lying to you and everyone else.
-我是個騙子  -快點
- I'm a liar. - Now!
快把手放在儀表盤上
Put your hands on the dash now.
快點  弗蘭克  照他們說的做
Do what... Frank, do what they say, now.
-下車  -對不起
- Get out of the car. - I'm sorry.
-不  不  -下車
- No, no, no. - Out of the car.
弗蘭克
Frank!
-不  先生  別過來  -弗蘭克
- No, sir, stand back, sir, stop. - Frank!
他什麼都沒做  別碰他
He's not doing anything. Leave him alone.
弗蘭克  弗蘭克
Frank, Frank!
靠
Shit.
弗蘭克  弗蘭克  弗蘭克
Frank, Frank, Frank!
我們印了
We printed,
學區的宣傳冊
pamphlets for the school district.
手冊之類的
Handbooks and such.
"我們"
We?
只有我
Me.
言辭力量只有我一個員工
WordPower was just me.
沒有合夥人
No partners.
我這麼問是因為
I only ask because
你公司一半的收入
it looks like half your corporation's earnings
似乎都轉至弗朗西斯·A·塔索內名下了
were transferred over to one Francis A. Tassone.
你不能逼我
You can't make me.
你不能
No, you, you can't...
逼我指證我的配偶
make me testify against my spouse.
配偶
Spouse?
我們是同居伴侶
We're domestic partners.
我們已經在一起三十三年了
We've been together 33 years.
我們有權得到聯邦保護
We're entitled to federal protections.
你們正式結婚了嗎
Are you legally wed?
我想起來了
You know something?
我們問詢過的人都說塔索內
Everybody we spoke to said Tassone
提起過他有個配偶  老婆
did talk about a spouse, a wife.
但她已經去世很久了
But that she'd been dead for some time.
三十多年了
Thirty-odd years or something.
你記得吧  他桌上那張新娘照片
You remember that, the bridal photo he had on his desk.
我們查出她的名字了嗎
We ever get a name on her?
別說了
Stop it.
別說什麼
Stop what?
你肯定也見過吧
I mean, you must have seen it, too.
你肯定經常去他的辦公室
I'm sure you were over by his office all the time
畢竟你每年承接學校八十萬美元的工作
what with that $800,000 job you were doing for the school.
好吧
Okay.
我們換個話題
Let's try another avenue.
你是否知道
Were you aware...
你的伴侶
that your partner...
今年早些時候在內華達州買了一處房產
closed on a property in Nevada earlier this year
和另一個男人一起
with another man?
他是個舞者
He's a dancer.
這媯o生了一件可怕的事
A terrible thing happened here.
而且不僅是錢的問題
And it's not just the money.
問題是對學校的信任
It's about trust in our schools.
制度的廉正
The integrity of our institutions.
我不知道怎麼才能從這件事中恢復過來
I don't know how we ever recover from this.
家長和老師間的關係不復以往
It was never the same between the parents and teachers.
事發後他們對我們的態度就變了
They treated us differently after that.
好像我們知情
Like we knew.
好像我們知情不報一樣
Like we had any idea at all.
我們當然希望能早點發現問題
Of course we wish we would have found out about this earlier.
但是一帆風順的時候
You know, when things are going well,
誰想沒事找事呢
who wants to go huntin' for problems?
他不辭辛勞
He went out of his way.
如果你需要任何幫助
If we ever needed anything from him
他總是笑臉相迎
he was there with a smile.
所以大家都順心
So we were all happy.
所以沒人質疑
So we didn't ask questions.
於是這個騙子和他的男友
So you have this, this liar and his boyfriend
在這個城市媔╳x若步
trotting around in the city in God knows what.
他蒙蔽了我們的雙眼
He just pulled the wool over our eyes.
我還能說什麼  真的很噁心
You know, what can I say? It's sick, it is.
回想起過去那麼多年的
You think back over the smaller moments,
一些細節  他給人...
over the years where he just seemed...
我說不好  他給人感覺很真誠
I don't know, he just seemed so real.
很真誠
So real.
謝謝
Thanks.
主編
沒事  我知道  我懂
No, I know. I know you do.
即將畢業的高三學生
The outgoing seniors.
考進常春藤院校的人數打破了記錄
They're going to the Ivy League in unprecedented numbers.
這是史上第一次
It was the first year on record
考進每所院校的人數
that we had admission offers from each school
都增多了
going up!
到底是什麼原因
And what changed?
是什麼讓我們這所小小的公立學校
What makes our little public school
在長島的眾多學校中鶴立雞群
so different from all the others like ours on Long Island?
更不要提全國範圍了
Let alone in the country at large.
說到底
At the end of the day,
我認為關鍵是廉正
I think it boils down to integrity.
我們的教員
Integrity in our faculty,
我們的課程
in our classrooms and curriculum,
以及我們親力親為  思維開闊的教學理念的廉正
and our approach to a broad-minded, hands-on education.
誠然  這些口號都被喊爛了
That's all the stuff that gets thrown around all the time, sure.
但在我的職業生涯中
But never in my career
我從未見過對這些素質的這種熱情
have I seen such passion for all these factors.
然後再加上著眼大局的意識
And then, paired with the willingness to think big.
你們知道自己為何而來
You know why you're here.
你們知道這對我們鎮的意義
You know what this means for our town.
但我要向你們介紹一位英雄
But I'm gonna tell you about one man who's a hero
沒有他這一切都不可能實現
without whom none of this would be possible.
拿第一不可一蹴而就
You don't get to number one overnight.
要花費多年的心血
It takes years of hard work.
而這是一個
And this is really a man
真正懂得合作的男人
who knows what it means to work together.
弗蘭克·塔索內上任之前
Before Frank Tassone...
沒有社區服務
There was no community service.
沒有公眾宣傳
There was no public outreach.
沒有天橋
There was no SkyWalk.
這個男人為學校奉獻了太多
This is a man who has given the school so much.
幹得漂亮
Magnificent.
祝賀你
Congratulations.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
請和我一起歡迎他上台
please join me in welcoming the man
他重整了我們的孩子們的學校
who whipped our kids' schools into shape
讓我們登上了第一
and got us all the way to number one!
你成功了  弗蘭克
You did it, Frank.
第一  第一  第一
Number one, number one, number one!
弗蘭克·塔索內被判從羅斯林學區盜竊220萬美元
並被判處四至十二年有期徒刑
帕梅拉·格盧金承認挪用公款430萬美元
並作證指控塔索內  她被判處三至九年有期徒刑
羅斯林學區總共被盜1100萬美元
使本案成為美國歷史上最大的學校盜竊案
《紐約時報》  《新聞日報》以及三州地區的
所有報紙都報道了這一醜聞
但都是在羅斯林高中的校報
《山峰燈塔》捅破新聞之後
由於紐約州養老金法案中的一處疏忽
弗蘭克·塔索內仍然享有每年173495.04美元的退休金
壞教育